Guide to the John G. Magee Family Papers
Magee Family (John G.) Papers
- Writings, 1906 2016; Series III
  - Writings of Faith B. Magee
    - "Cat Thoughts", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Poetry written by Faith B. Magee, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Writings of John G. Magee, Jr.
    - Composition/Handwriting Notebooks, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Essays written while at Rugby School, 1935 1939 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Poetry and plays written while at Rugby School, 1935 1939 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Poems - includes original manuscripts and typescripts, 1936 1941 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Printed copies of "High Flight" are located in the Personal Items and Memorabilia series.
    - Poems - includes original manuscripts and typescripts, 1936 1941 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Souvenir edition of original book of poems published by JGM Jr. in 1939, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Writings of F. Hugh Magee
    - Sermon - "Transfiguration", 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "Alumni Perspective" essay in newsletter of Episcopal Church at Yale, regarding FHM's time at Yale and his father's work as Episcopal Chaplain at Yale, 2009 Apr (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Book - An Upgrader's Guide: How to move on from Christianity and rediscover Jesus (CreateSpace), 2010 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Book - Hacking Obsolete Beliefs with a Course in Miracles, 2016 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Book - Required to Love: A Memoir, 2019 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Writings of Christopher W. Magee
    - "The Magees of Pittsburgh", No date (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Nanking Documentation, 1937 2004; Series IV
  For films related to Nanking documentation, see Series VI.
  - Correspondence and Documents
    - Copies of letters from John G. Magee (for originals see Series I: Correspondence), 1937 1938 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Incomplete typescripts of John G. Magee's letters from Nanking, 1937 1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Partial and incomplete documents regarding Nanking, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Story told to John G. Magee by Mrs. Tuan-Muh Ching-chen on March 22, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Radio Broadcast Typescripts, Publications, and Reports
    - "Nanking Yesterday and Today." Talk by John G. Magee made at the Nanking Broadcasting Station, 1937 May 28 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - China Press. Nanking Edition, 1937 Sep 15 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Notes from Broadcasts - Sunday evening, 1937 Oct 3 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - National Christian Council of China - Broadcasts from Shanghai, 1937 December 1938 January (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - National Christian Council of China - Broadcasts from Shanghai, 1938 February 1938 March (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - National Christian Council of China - Broadcasts from Shanghai, 1938 May 1938 June (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - National Christian Council of China News Bulletin, No.1 and Confidential Supplement, 1938 Jun 20 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - N.C.D.N. Broadcast, [1938?] Jan 26 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Japanese Propaganda regarding Nanking, 1938 Jan 8 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Report of a Trip to Tsih Hsia Shan, John G. Magee, 1938 February 16 1938 February 17 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - The Japan Advertiser. Tokyo., 1938 Apr 5 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - China Information Committee News Release No.230 and 236, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "A Call for Unwavering Loyalty," China Information Committee, Hankou (Hankow), China, 1938 September 20 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Experiences in and around Hankou (Hankow), Published by The British Fund for the Relief of Distress in China, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Report of the Nanking International Relief Committee, ca.1940 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - "Fresh Stories from China," by John G. Magee, ca.1940 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Chinese Document, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Doc. No. 9580. All Military Aggression in China Including Atrocities Against Civilians and Others: Summary of Evidence and Note of Argument, Submitted by David Nelson Sutton, 1946 Nov 4 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Notes regarding Japan after 1946, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Photographs and Films
    Films also listed under Series VI, Photographs and Films
    - Atrocities in Nanking photographs, 1937 1938 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - John G. Magee's notes regarding the Nanking Films, 1937 1938 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Notes regarding the Nanking Films, 1937 1938 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - John G. Magee's Nanking Massacre 16mm positive film (2 reels) and DVD copies, 1937 1938 (Box OV1)
    - Magee film received 2015: Reel 1, 1937 1938 (Box 22)
      See description of Reel 1 in Series VI, Photographs and Films
    - Magee film received 2015: Reel 9, 1937 1938 (Box 23)
      See description of Reel 9 in Series VI, Photographs and Fillms
    - Copy of Library of Congress Magee footage (DVD) (Box OV1)
  - Nanking Documentation Collected by David B. Magee: Correspondence
    - Alliance in Memory of Victims of the Nanjing Massacre, 1991 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Alliance in Memory of Victims of the Nanjing Massacre, 1993 1998 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Chang, Iris - regarding her book, The Rape of Nanking, also includes news clippings and articles regarding her book, 1996 2004 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Izumitani, Akiko - regarding Documentary Film Project, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - St. Louis Alliance for Preserving the Truth of Sino-Japanese War, also includes news clippings, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence regarding Nanking, 1991 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence regarding Nanking, 1995 1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence regarding Nanking, 2000 2004 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Nanking Documentation Collected by David B. Magee: Conferences and Documentary Film Showings
    - Global Memorial Conference of the 57th Anniversary of the "Rape of Nanjing", 1994 Dec 10 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Film - "In the Name of the Emperor", Christine Choy and Nancy Tong, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Nanking Massacre Conference - Princeton, 1997 November 17 1997 November 22 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Third Biennial Conference of the Global Alliance for Preserving the History of WWII in Asia, Toronto, Canada (includes photographs), 1998 October 16 1998 October 18 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Collected Correspondence and Material related to David B. Magee's donation of John G. Magee's Bell and Howell camera to the Nanjing Massacre Memorial Hall and trip to Nanjing, China, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "Remarks by David B. Magee" made at various events, 1996 2000 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of David B. Magee attending various conferences regarding Nanking Massacre, 1994 2002 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Nanking Documentation Collected by David B. Magee: Articles and Newspaper Clippings
    - Collected Articles, 1938; 1980 1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Collected Articles, 1990 2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1937 1940 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1989 1991 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1992 1995 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1996 1999 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 2000 2004 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1990 1999 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Other Collected Material, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Nanking Documentation Collected by F. Hugh Magee
    - Script of "December Hell - Nanking in Sorrow: Confession and Repentence", play by Yoshiji Watanabe and Kazuko Yokoi, 2007 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Photograph of tribute to Magee Family presented by Alliance in Memory of the Victims of the Nanjing Massacre; clippings regarding documentary film Nanking, 2003; 2008 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1902 2011; Series V
  - John G. and Faith B. Magee family
    - John G. Magee's date books and letter books
      - Date book, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Date book, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Date book, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Date book, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Date book, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Date book, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Address book, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Letter books, 1912 1924 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Letter book, 1942 1946 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Notebook of Faith Backhouse Magee
      - Record of letters and notes, 1962 1971 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Documents
      - John G. Magee's Diploma from Episcopal Theological School, 1911 (Box OV2)
      - John G. Magee's Chinese Passport, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Faith B. Magee's Passports, Prayer card, Certificate of Registration, "Family Events" booklet, 1918 1962 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - John G. Magee's Passports, 1925; 1928; 1931; 1940; 1946 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Marriage Announcement, 1921 Jul 19 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Certificate of Marriage, 1921 Jul 19 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Birth Certificates - David B. Magee, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - John G. Magee's Fidelity Title and Trust Company, Trust Agreement, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Faith Magee's Medical Adviser's Report, Department of Missions of the Protestant Episcopal Church, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Will of Miss Ruth M. Backhouse (Faith B. Magee's sister), 1942 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Copy of Remuneration of Trust by John G. Magee, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Birth certificate of F. Hugh Magee, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Certificate from the Memorial for the Victims of the Nanjing Massacre by Japanese Invaders acknowledging the donation of JGM's camera to the Memorial, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Biographical Information
      - John G. Magee, Stowe's Clerical Directory entry, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - John G. Magee Obituaries and Memorials, 1953 Sep (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Sermon given by The Rev. S.M. Shoemaker at the Memorial Service for John G. Magee, "The Memory of a Good Man", 1953 Sep 13 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Faith B. Magee's Visit to Buckingham Palace, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Faith B. Magee's Obituary and Cavalry Episcopal Church Order for the Burial of the Dead, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Biographical Information regarding David B. and Christopher W. Magee, 1945 1947 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Obituary, memorial service program, and Hugh Magee's eulogy for David Magee (1925-2013) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Memorabilia
      - Yale University Scrapbook, 1902 1906 (Box OV2)
      - Ticket to Yale-Harvard Football Game, 1905 Nov 25 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Sermon preached by The Rev. E.B. Backhouse (Faith B. Magee's father), 1914 Aug 9 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Caroline Batt Backhouse Memorial Service, 1928 Jul 14 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - St. Clare History and St. Clare Magazines, Upper Walmer, England (School attended by John G. Magee, Jr. and David B. Magee), 1932; 1935 1939 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Qingdao (Tsingtao) Place Cards (hand-drawn place cards for Magee family); greeting card; booklet about Chinese festivals, 1937 1941 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - St. John's Church, Washington, DC, 1944 1946 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - David B. Magee's U.S. War Ration Book Four, ca.1944 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - John G. Magee's Yale Stationery; invitation to inauguration of Alfred Whitney Griswold as President of Yale University, 1946 1950 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - Business Cards, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - Chinese Writings, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 27)
      - Two Photographs of Chinese Students of John G. Magee, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 28)
      - Collected Poetry, 1944, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - Collected Memorabilia - Various, including poster for St. Marks, Bury Xmas Fayre opened by Faith B. Magee, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 30)
      - "Descendants of Thomas Backhouse, Yeoman, of Kirkland, Caldbeck, Cumberland, Died 1743." Compiled by Brigadier E.H.W. Backhouse (Faith B. Magee's brother), 1959 (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - "Your Clan Heritage: Clan Mackay." Compiled by Alan McNie, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - Miscellaneous genealogical and family history documentation (Box 24, Folder 3-6)
      - "Sinatra I'm Not" - musical program by David B. Magee and recitation of "High Flight" poem by DBM (Box OV1)
      - "Magee Home Recordings" (CD and 5 original records), 1939 (Box OV1)
    - Magee Family newspaper clippings and scrapbooks
      - Newspaper clippings, 1920 1939 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1940 1949 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1950 1959 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1960 1969 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1970 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1980 1989 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1990 1999 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Magee family scrapbook, includes newspaper clippings, photographs, and correspondence, 1870 1965 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Scrapbook of Faith Magee, including newspaper clippings, photographs, and correspondence, 1950 1963 (Box OV4)
    - Collected Material
      - American Missionary Eyewitnesses to the Nanking Massacre, 1937-1938. Edited by Martha Lund Smalley. Yale Divinity School Library Occasional Publication No.9: New Haven, CT, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - History of the Class of 1906 Yale College, Vol. I. Edited by George Starkweather Fowler. Yale University: New Haven, CT (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - History of the Class of 1906 Yale College, Vol. II. Edited by Edwin Rogers Embree. Yale University Press: New Haven, CT, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Lorant, Stephan. Pittsburgh: The Story of an American City. Doubleday Company, Inc.: Garden City, NY, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Church, Samuel Harden. A Short History of Pittsburgh. DeVinne Press, NY, 1908 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Descriptive Guide of Calvary Church, Pittsburgh, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - "A Gift to Pittsburgh: Magee-Womens Hospital of UPMC" by Nancy Kennedy, 2014 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Material related to Yale Hope Mission and the Episcopal Church at Yale, 1953 1994 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Awards
      - The Zijin Grass International Commemorative Medal of Peace, 2017 (Box 25)
        This medal was accepted on behalf of the Magee family by Christopher Magee (grandson of John G. Magee) in Nanjing in 2017. The main pattern on the medal is the Zijin Grass, or Violet Orychopragmus, a familiar plant for Nanjing residents. In the center of the medal is a seal with the character yi, meaning justice and symbolizing the foreigners' brave defense of justice and priceless love for Nanjing refugees.
  - John G. Magee, Jr.
    - Documents
      - Birth Certificate, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Baby record book, 1922 1930 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Journal of trip from China to England, with illustrations, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Passport, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Oxford Cambridge Schools Examination Board - School Certificate A, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Flight Log (photocopy), 1941 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Documents regarding death and burial of John G. Magee, Jr., 1941 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Biographical Information
      - Articles and documents about John G. Magee, Jr. and "High Flight" collected by David B. Magee, 1941 1993 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Articles and documents related to John G. Magee, Jr. and "High Flight" collected by F. Hugh Magee, 1937 2011 (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
      - Hagedorn, Hermann. Sunward I've Climbed: The Story of John Magee, Poet and Soldier, 1922-1941. Macmillan Company: New York, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Cole, Roger High Flight: The Life and Poetry of Pilot Officer John Gillespie Magee. Fighting High, Ltd., 2013 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - High Flight
      - Illuminated copies of the poem, "High Flight", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Magee Memorial, Triptych, Bolling Field, Washington, DC, including photograph and correspondence (painted by Alfred James Tulk, 1899-1988), 1945 1958 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - "High Flight" printed in Pittsburgh's Family Magazine, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - "High Flight" Musical Composition, by Johan Franco, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Collected material regarding "High Flight", 1941 1996 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Lewis Meyer's Original Program, "The Values We Live By," dedicated to John G. Magee, Jr., Nov. 11, 1942, KTUL Tulsa, OK (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - "High Flight" Adaptations and Parodies (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - High Flight Scrapbook, includes original correspondence, newspaper clippings, and poems, 1923 1945 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - "Touching the Face of God: The Story of John Gillespie Magee, Jr. and his Poem 'High Flight'" by Ray Haas, 2014 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Memorabilia
      - Play Bill - "The First and The Last," with John G. Magee, Jr. as Larry Darrant, ca.1939 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Photocopies of John G. Magee, Jr. Material
      - Henson photocopies of John G. Magee, Jr. material, various (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Henson photocopies of John G. Magee, Jr. material, various (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Henson photocopies of John G. Magee, Jr. material, various (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Henson photocopies of John G. Magee, Jr. material, various (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Henson photocopies of John G. Magee, Jr. material, various (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Henson photocopies of John G. Magee, Jr. material, various (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Henson photocopies of John G. Magee, Jr. material, various (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Extended family
- Photographs and Films, 1870 1965; Series VI
  - Photographs
    - John G. Magee
      - Group portrait of athletic team, ca.1902 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Student group portraits, ca.1902 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Album from time at Hotchkiss School, 1901 1902 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Group portrait of Hotchkiss Athletic Association track team, JGM manager, 1901 1902 (Box OV3)
      - Group portrait of unidentified Yale club, 1903 1906 (Box OV3)
        Group includes William Whiting Borden, co-founder of the Yale Hope Mission with JGM in 1907.
      - Group portrait of unidentified Yale club, 1903 1905 (Box OV3)
      - Group portrait of Yale Glee Club, 1904 (Box OV3)
      - Group portrait of Yale football team, 1905 (Box OV3)
      - Group portrait of Yale hockey team, ca.1905 (Box OV2)
      - Group portrait of Yale students, including John G. Magee, ca.1906 (Box OV2)
      - Early years in China, 1912 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Early years in China, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Early years in China, 1914 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Early years in China, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Early years in China, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Early years in China, 1917 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Group portrait taken in China, ca.1930 (Box OV2)
      - Group portraits, 1920 1945 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Portraits, ca.1920, ca.1935 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Portraits, 1940 1949 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Portrait, ca.1950 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - John G. Magee and Sam Shoemaker, ca.1950 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Magee family portraits, 1930 1942 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Magee family photographs - various, 1930 1940 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Additional photos of Magee and immediate family (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Faith B. Magee
      - Backhouse family photographs, 1880 1919 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Portrait, 1919 1929 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Wedding portrait, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - Portrait, 1930 1939 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Portrait, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - Portrait, 1950 1959 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - Framed portrait, ca.1965 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - John G. Magee, Jr.
      - Portrait, 1930 1939 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - St. Clare's - John G. Magee, Jr.and David Magee, 1932 1933 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - Portrait taken at Avon School, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - Portrait, ca.1940 (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Royal Canadian Air Force portraits, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Royal Canadian Air Force photographs, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Royal Canadian Air Force group portraits, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Portrait, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Photograph album re. JGM Jr., 1930 1939 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Album of photos and clippings related to JGM Jr's service with Royal Canadian Air Force, including training sites, 1941 (Box OV3)
    - Other loose photographs
      - View of Nanking, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Church compound, Nanking [Nanjing], 1993 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Reproductions of China photographs, 1930 1939 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Additional photographs taken in China (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Reproductions of various Magee family photographs, 1930 1949 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Photographs of extended family and friends, 1910 1958 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Additional photographs of extended family, including Backhouse, Walford, Gillespie branches (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Unidentified photographs, 1915 1930 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Scenes in England, Aden, and Maine (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Portrait of Rex Flinn with his wife and child, 1918 (Box OV3)
        Alexander Rex Flinn was JGM's best friend, a fellow Yale graduate
      - Miscellaneous photos, 1900 1941 (Box 26, Folder 4)
        Including group portrait of Chinese and Western individuals taken by C.H.Wong Photo Studio, Shanghai (ca.1930s)
    - Miscellaneous albums and framed photographs
      - Album of European post cards, 1905 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Album with scenes from England and Europe, No date (Box 26, Folder 2)
        Likely from a trip taken by Backhouse family
      - Magee and Backhouse family photograph album, 1870 1920 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Backhouse and Magee family photograph album, 1880 1938 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Magee family album, 1908 1913 (Box OV4)
        Album has captions. Photos range from JGM's trip to South America in 1908 with his mother to see her sister, the "Baroness" to JGM's work on the Winnebago Indian reservation to scenes en route to China to famine and rebellion in China, Kuling and Hsiakwan areas.
      - Backhouse family photograph album, 1915 1930 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Photograph album with captions written by Faith Magee (includes photograph from John and Faith Magee's wedding, 1921 1922 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Pages from photograph album with captions by Faith Magee, 1916 1921 (Box OV4)
        Includes photos of missionaries in China, wedding of JGM and FBM, Magee children, scenes in the U.S. and Canada
      - Photograph album - China, 1930 1939 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Magee family photograph album, 1930 1939 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Magee family photograph album, 1930 1939 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Magee family photograph album - mostly David and Christopher Magee, 1940 1949 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Magee family photograph album, 1920 1960 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Framed photograph of John G. Magee's siblings, ca.1890 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Framed photograph of "Rosehill" house in Evergreen Hamlet, outside Pittsburgh, ca.1900 (Box OV3)
        "Rosehill" at 164 Rock Ridge Rd, Evergreen Hamlet was the last home of JGM from ca. 1949 to his death in 1953. The home was previously owned by the McCallums, cousins of JGM.
      - Album of photos of "Rosehill", 1909 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Framed photograph of (Margaret) Louise Magee Riedl de Ridenau (Baroness), 1906 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Films and videos
    See notes related to films in Box 6 Folders 29-30
    - Films made by John Magee
      - John G. Magee's Nanking Massacre 16mm positive film (2 reels) and DVD copies (Box OV1)
        Existence and Location of Copies
        DVD copy available
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 1, 1937 1938 (Box 22)
        Scenes of refugees on Ginling College campus, including Minnie Vautrin and Ernest Forster.
        Digital file available
      - Magee 16mm film received in 2015 - Reel 2, no date (Box 22)